[Music]
w
hello good evening everybody good day
everybody wherever you are and welcome
back to the ask abijit show I hope
you're do all doing fantastic you're all
doing great and before we get into the
the show let me see who all is there on
the live chat I can see a lot of
people air defense power Alvin Rodriguez
random skull rishab dang feminist Slayer
Shaman ra Samar tripati ainash
Shani deep Anita Shri ramachandra namaha
thha J value Clips Abhishek haa
geopolitical dub from indor thees is
back good to see you thees I hope you're
doing well take care yourself my friend
God's servant vinit Savant shagun Chopra
good to see you as well tanai Chandra
Shri Ram Nam again GI political dub good
to see you as well sir uh Krishna goind
Alfred ragunath bul Rai from
Surinam uh grimo bad pram Agarwal Manny
Bo ocean Oscar Madison suim data meganes
Kos Sunil Seal Seal b n ningombam
RK
vishnoi solo Rider Akay ra who all do we
have the ancient speed vidan Sharma
Sachin H warun suran Kapil nikil Kumar
McLovin hello Sunil Mahala Barat Kumar
Kahan barwad Richard pren Jay guman
Vishnu moan gurukant Muk toan Chri MRI
Krishna Amisha Mishra hello ma'am Nova
bumblebee Eisen hello cap SAA first off
chinari S Su Shashank Mis agnostic human
pram Agarwal Vin Krishna Manisha cardoo
and lots and lots and lots of other
people the Conqueror Sam Satish and
everybody else greetings to all of you
and thank you so much for being on this
live stream with that done a lot of
greetings let's get into the questions
I'm going to take questions from um that
you all have asked in the comments and
later if possible I'll take some from
the live chat as well let's begin with
the first question what's the first
question okay this is from X from
Twitter sumeo says why is US president
Trump Donald Trump so so interested why
is he so interested in in making
Bitcoin and
cryptocurrency uh a part of the US
strategic Reserve so why is he creating
a you an American strategic Reserve
which includes which is dedicated to
cryptocurrencies essentially what's
happening is that Trump is interested in
making Bitcoin and various other
cryptocurrencies into a strategic
Reserve asset for the United States and
why is this happening that's the
question and he has recently signed an
order to create a strategic bit Bitcoin
or crypto reserve for the United States
so this move by Trump it's part of his
uh effort his push to position his the
United States as the world's crypto
capital cryptocurrency capital and he
recently announced a crypto Summit that
there's going to be a crypto Summit he
announced that recently and uh in this
strategic Reserve there's going to be
various uh cryptocurrencies that will be
included such as bit Bitcoin ethereum
Solana cardano and xrp and various other
cryptocurrencies so this strategic
Reserve will hold cryptocurrencies that
have been uh
seized by the US government in legal
proceedings in in court cases in in
various legal
proceedings and uh this is going to be
kind of like uh the Strategic gold
reserves that the United States has at
Fort
Knox so is this a big deal it's kind of
a big deal because it's the first time
the US government is treating Bitcoin
and crypto as a valuable asset similar
to the way governments have historically
treated gold every nation has gold
assets right a certain amount of gold
assets uh few hundreds of tons of of
gold or thousands of tons of gold you
you hold that in reserve uh because gold
is the number one in imperishable asset
so now the us is going to treat crypto
cryptocurrency and Bitcoin especially
similar to The Way We generally treat
gold and uh uh how much Bitcoin or
crypto does the US government have I
think they estimated they have about
200,000 2 lakh uh Bitcoins that they
have seized thus far which essentially
is worth several billion dollars not
sure exactly what it is you can if it's
200,000 you can figure out you can
calculate it based on the current going
rate for what Bitcoin and it's going to
be a few billion dollars so instead of
selling these Bitcoins they're going to
keep them as a long-term investment and
see it's it's not a bad idea because it
doesn't cost the US taxpayer anything
and if the value of Bitcoin goes up and
uh it could be really beneficial to the
United States so just to put this in the
right context what's Bitcoin what's
cryptocurrency it's it's different from
regular money because there especially
when it comes to bitcoin there's a
limited amount of it so it's a good way
to protect against
inflation uh so that's why it's it's a
it's a good idea and it shows that the
US and Trump are they're taking digital
currencies seriously and they want to
make and keep America a leader they want
to keep America a leader in the global
economy and this would give the US uh
various options more options in dealing
with other countries especially in
situations where regular banking may not
work whether you want to fund some kind
of regime change operation or you want
to fund so-called Freedom Fighters in
various parts of the world and so on
okay so that's a deal of course this has
some risks bitcoin's value can fluctuate
it can and uh it can it can drop also
which has happened I suppose in the past
so that could be a problem I'm sure
everybody doesn't agree it's a good idea
but uh and I'm sure there are certain
political arguments against this but
overall I think the US government is
trying to be Forward Thinking and and
staying in in tune with the times so
that's the deal uh with Trump creating a
Bitcoin and cryptocurrency strategic
reserve for his
country Mr 88s says why is birel Still
Still unclaimed and uninhabited will
this issue ever get
resolved or will both Sudan or are both
Sudan and Egypt secretly preparing for
war in the long run beel let's find out
what be is where's the map we need to go
to the map my friends where's the map
here is map yes so let's put the map on
the screen and now we're going to take a
look at where be th is so you all know
where India is yes we're going to go
westwards we're going to cross the
Arabian Peninsula and here we are at the
border between Egypt and Sudan as you
can see it's a straight line and you can
see dashed lines over here right so this
big roughly triangular like region
that's a disputed territory okay and
this smaller region which is now in kind
of in the middle of the screen let's
zoom in zoom in zoom in this region is
is called be Tavel and this other region
which is kind of triangular is called
the Hal triangle so both Nations Egypt
and Sudan claim this territory the halib
triangle Egypt administers it and
neither Nation wants
beerel and if you look at it from the
satellite imagery perspective you can
see it's mostly Baron land um desert and
there's no vegetation
and nothing essentially okay so that
kind of gives us a clue one of the clues
as to why be is something neither Nation
wants so the smaller territory in the
dash line is is bir the larger one is
the Hal triangle so what's the deal now
so to give you a very brief introduction
as to what's going on and why
be nobody wants it it it remains
unclaimed it is unclaimed by both
Nations and because it's a rather low
value piece of territory it's a very
harsh desert region uh there is no human
inhabitation it's it's terrible it's not
good for habitation there's no human
inhabitation and it's extremely harsh
there are no
strategic reasons why Any Nation would
want it there are no economic reasons
why anybody would want it there's no
political reason there are no political
incentives for either Nation to claim it
there's no water there's no resources
there's no access to the the the ocean
there are no development opportunities
there nothing it's completely unsuitable
for habitation now put putting let's put
this back on the screen and understand
the historical context as to how these
these things happen these these disputes
and whatever else happens as as you can
see if we zoom out if you look at the
borders of various nations in Africa you
will see you will see lots and lots of
straight lines even in the West Asia
region you will see lots of straight
lines and if you look at Egypt's borders
it's just straight lines more or less
now how did this happen it's all the
consequence of
colonization okay Colonial Powers decide
they arbitrarily decide what the lines
on the map are going to be and that's
the root cause of so many of the
problems that plague and and bevil the
African countries that exist today so uh
there is a there was a historical border
dispute between Egypt and Sudan which is
uh which originates in decisions made by
the United Kingdom in the colonial era
so
late 19th century almost at the cusp of
the 20th century the British established
this politic this this straight line
boundary which is I think called the
22nd parallel parallel between Egypt and
Sudan and they placed this region of be
let's put put that back on the screen
and the British put birl in Sudan
okay then a couple of years later like
two three years later the British Drew
an administrative an ad hoc
administrative boundary based on some
apparently some some land used by
tribals or whatever and they drew this
boundary and in this boundary they
placed birl under Egyptian
administration because of some tribal
land use or whatever so they first made
the straight line map then they changed
their mind and placed bir and Egyptian
Administration and so on so the so that
is the origin of this matter but uh
there's a parallel issue which is the
dispute over the Hal triangle so this
Hal triangle is way more valuable okay
and both Nations claim this and
strangely because of this claim neither
Nation wants to claim
Beav so according to what what we call
inter international law which
essentially is the treaties Etc that
both nations are party to so according
to inter under the the framework of
international law for whatever reason
I've not L looked into the details
apparently there is no legal basis for
either country to claim both territories
simultaneously and both nations want the
Hal triangle and nobody therefore wants
to claim the useless Beav which is why
it remains unclaimed nobody goes there
nobody no neither country has any
framework Administration governance over
there completely baren no
resources okay so it's one of the rare
unclaimed territories in the world so
I'm not sure what the details of the
international law thing are which uh
which ensure that neither Nation can
claim both territories simultaneously
but if you want you can look into it so
both Nations won the Hal triangle this
has resources this has water this has
access to the ocean which is the red see
and there is habitation as well over
here as you can see there's habitation
and so on so that's the deal is one of
the
strange cases one of the rare cases of a
territory that is uninhabited and and
and unclaimed By Any Nation and I I
believe there have been attempts in the
past by various people just for fun I
suppose to to call it a micro nation and
so on but uh and I suppose anybody can
travel there to beerav either
through Sudan if you are courageous
enough to go there or via Egypt but I
would not recommend going to be because
there's no government there and yeah you
may end up in trouble so better not go
there so that's the deal with
beerel prai Paul says Trump hails the
reclaiming of the Panama canel after a
black rock Le group acquires a stick
what's the significance of the this in
Regional and Global geopolitics does
this further confirm that companies like
Black Rock function as an arm of the
deep
State okay so what's happened is that
the US gigantic company called Black
Rock has acquired the Panama Canal
where's the Panama Canal in case you
want to see let's put that on the screen
where's the map where's the
map here's the map so it's in Central
America there's this nation called
called Panama
and there's this canel that goes through
Panama City and so on and it's an
artificial canel that the Americans
built and in the past and it connects
the two the two great oceans the
Atlantic Ocean and the Pacific Ocean if
this canal did not exist like it did not
in the past then historically ships had
to go all the way down south and cross
the horrific and they had to go around
the horrific Cape
Horn and if you know anything about Cape
Horn it's it's a dreaded Place terrible
terrible weather so many ships get
wrecked over here uh so it's not a good
place to go to so that's why and it
takes so much more time to round the
entire continent right so the Panama
Canal is an extremely important
geopolitical strategic choke
point and black rock has acquired this
so the US government did not need did
not need to send soldiers or the
military or whatever there Black Rock
simply has acquired this and now it's a
US
possession so obviously it's very
significant it gives the US control over
one of the most important uh Geographic
choke points in the world one of the
most strategic choke points in the world
and the us obviously will over time you
know have a significant Naval Etc
presence in the region and so on that
will happen uh so they essentially now
own this strategic choke point uh this
definitely confirms that gigantic
corporations like black Black Rock
essentially are extensions of the US
government and whatever you want to call
it the Deep state or whatever absolutely
no question about it uh so yeah it's a
fa comply uh the Donald Trump was
talking about acquiring the the Panama
Canal they have acquired it it doesn't
matter how you acquire it you got to
acquire it you don't need to see see
when you have a nation like the US that
has so many options they don't need to
use the military for everything they
don't need to you know launch an
invasion of Panama they just acquire
this they just buy it through one of
their proxies so yeah Black Rock
certainly is an arm of the US
establishment the US government of the
United States as an as a geopolitical
entity and they have got this done so
what is next is it Mexico is it uh
Canada is it
Greenland what is it that's a
question prar Gupta says do you think
Trump has gone mad after his recent
statements about Canada the Gulf of
Mexico and Greenland do these statements
have any substance in them look uh if if
we go to the map which
is uh this is Google Maps right if you
go there if you go to Google Maps and
you go to the Gulf of Mexico what do we
find here Gulf of Mexico in in into
brackets Gulf of America so Trump has
already renamed this as the Gulf of
America and right now we are seeing a
transition phase in Google Maps it's
called it's still called Gulf of Mexico
but they placing Gulf of America in into
brackets and eventually they're going to
re they're going to get rid of this gulf
of Mexico term and it's simply going to
be called Gulf of the Gulf of America so
that's done it's just a symbolic thing I
mean uh the us is a way more powerful
Nation so obviously they can name it as
per their choice fine um so that is done
what about Canada so Trump calls Justin
trudo the governor of the great state of
Canada right he doesn't call him the
prime minister of Canada and he calls
Canada the great state of Canada not the
great nation of Canada uh so the
Americans have always essentially owned
Canada but it's technically a separate
country and if they want they're going
to get this done as well they can simply
integrate Canada into the United States
as one of the territories maybe the 51st
state or or whichever way they want to
do it maybe make it a territory similar
to what Puerto Rico is we'll we'll see
they can do it anytime they want they
can do it uh the hardware they can do it
very nicely uh there's nothing the
Canadian government or the people can do
about this if the Americans decide to
incorporate Canada into their Nation now
the question is Greenland
Greenland is this territory it looks
very large over here it's not that large
but it's important and Trump says that
we need to acquire Greenland because
it's important to our national security
so Greenland technically belongs to
Denmark what is Denmark it's it's a
small little country over here it's one
of the Scandinavian countries one of the
earth while Viking countries and
Greenland for historical reasons will
not go into them it belongs to uh to
Denmark right so how does Trump acquire
Greenland how how does he get it done
what if Denmark
refuses to sell Greenland to the US so
what you do is this look Denmark is part
of the EU it's part of possibly NATO
it's it's a country that's essentially a
puppet of vasal of the us we all know
this so it can be arm Twisted through a
variety of ways and we'll not go into
the ways because it's not nice to talk
about those ways there's nothing violent
in here it's all economic terms and
various kinds of leverage you can apply
to make a nation capitulate and agree to
what you want so the first stage is How
Will trump acquire green land I think
he's going to acquire it okay so how
will he do this is the question okay
let's look at it step by step first step
is apply various kinds of pressure on
the government of Denmark the people who
are in the decision-making
uh capacity apply various kinds of
Leverage and pressure on these people so
after you do that after some time uh the
government of Denmark you will find will
agree to a referendum in Greenland does
Greenland want to remain part of Denmark
does it want to be independent or does
it want to become a part of the us
that's step number one so first you
apply pressure on the politicians they
capitulate and they agree to a
referendum then you set a date for the
referendum which is let's say 3 months 6
months in the future
now what you do if you are Donald Trump
is you go to the people of Greenland how
many what's the what's the population of
Greenland let's let's quickly take a
look shall we what's the population of
Greenland let's quickly take a look
let's Google that hey Google no
Greenland
population Greenland population is about
uh 56
57,000 okay so what Trump does now is
that once the date of the referendum is
set he makes a promise to the people of
Greenland I'm going to give each and
every citizen or or or resident of
Greenland $1 million if you become if
you if you vote to become a part of the
us so how much does does it cost the US
first of all it's 56865 right okay now
calculator
calculator so 56 865 56
let's just call it
57,000 okay you go give each of them a
million dollar 1 2 3 4 5 six how much is
it uh let's divide this by one with nine
zeros 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 it is $ 57
billion that's all it costs the United
States that's all it will cost
them $ 57 billion which is not a lot of
money it's peanuts it's small ch change
for the
US so imagine what a million dollars can
do to a person if you are a family of
let's say three people oh you know in
the west you have small families father
mother and one one child let's say and
the child is let's said five years old
you get $3 million as a family you're
life you're set for life if you are if
if you have any sense right so all Trump
has to do is to promise every single uh
citizen or resident of Greenland $1
million if Greenland votes to become
part of the
US done deal it's a done deal everybody
will jump at the opportunity let's all
vote and ensure we get a million dollars
each that's how easy it is that's how
easy it is and it's going to happen so
Greenland in my opinion is a done deal
sooner or later it's going to become a
part of the United States there we have
it okay what is
next samart says why did Dr SJ Shanker
say that Trump is good for India
especially in the in the context of a
multi-polar world recently Trump
announced reciprocal tariffs
particularly targeting India and Jo
Shankar hinted that the trade deal could
be possible though this is just
speculation what does this mean for
India us
relations okay so why did Dr J Shankar
said that Trump is good for India first
of all please understand whoever is the
president of the United States you have
to see this you have to say this person
is great for
us the US is the most powerful nation in
the world can a nation like India afford
to say this guy is bad for us can we
afford to say that does it make any any
logical sense to say something like that
you have to praise them you have to
flatter them that's that's number one
that's the first point I would like to
make you never say they are bad whoever
the president is secondly this is Donald
Trump and not Joe Biden or Kamala Harris
do you even remember what sort of
attitude and approach they had towards
India the Biden Harris Administration
they were downright evil towards India
they the the Democrats hate India they
have a great amount of antipathy towards
India historically they are great
supporters of
Pakistan and
they it's the Democrats who have
typically been been the ones funding all
kinds of anti-india activ is within
India for example rampant industrial
scale demographic religious change
christianization funding of missionary
organizations all of that all the human
rights abuses and claims they make about
India backsliding of democratic
backsliding the entire media Onslaught
against India hurting India through so
many different ways like the kooki land
for Christ thing that's happening in
Manipur who started this it was Victor
newand and and and her cronies who
started this right um the entire Myanmar
Civil War which has spilled over into
Manipur the the influx of lacks of
illegal infiltrators
cookies foreigners into India yes all
that the Bangladesh coup everything
support for Pakistan the Democrats have
historically being extraordinarily
anti-india and Trump is not that sort of
guy Trump has no issue with
India yeah so Trump is actually good for
India and why not say that please
understand that it's nothing to do with
the context of a unque bolar multipolar
or tripolar bipolar World it has nothing
to do with that Trump is actually good
for India of course he's going to
announce reciprocal tariffs he wants
wins for his country and he's not
announced reciprocal tariffs only for us
he's announced reciprocal tariffs
globally against every nation that has
tariffs against that imposes tariffs on
things it it imports from the US so if
you tax x number of items 20% I'm going
to tax all your items 20% that's of
thing so it's not aimed at India he
actually likes India and he has a great
amount of warmth towards Prime Minister
Modi now you think this tariffs issue is
going to be a big deal absolutely not
it's not going to be a thorn in the
India us or US India relationship first
of all understand this we tax American
Imports sure we have tariffs of our own
how much so when it comes to about 75 5%
of the stuff we import from from the US
75% of the items our tariffs are 5% or
less it's it's a nothing Burger it's
non-issue the other 25% we can discuss
it we can talk about it so when Trump
says I'm going to tax you I'm going to
I'm going to impose reciprocal tariffs
we will say sir please sir what's the
need we are we are willing to do
whatever you need
sir we will give you the win that you
want you can go and tell the American
people that I got the American I got the
Indians to do uh the right thing so
please sir let's Dis Let's sit down on
the negotiating table we will we will
send our Representatives you send your
your representatives we can sit down and
we can work it out there's no need to go
to have a trade War we don't want a
trade War we want friendship with the US
that's what the government of India is
going to say take it in writing we
cannot have a trade war with the US
Trump will squash any nation that tries
to have a trade war with
him we want to be on Trump's good side
so let's give him the wins that he
wants you if you're taxing his whis
American whiskey too much let's bring
the taxes down I I believe it's already
done I hear that lots of whiskey
officios are pretty Overjoyed American
bourbon whiskey is much cheaper now if
if Trump wants the tariffs on
Harley-Davidson motorcycles to come down
sure let's do it doesn't matter so my
point is it doesn't mean anything bad
for India us relations I think during
Trump's presidency India us relations
will reach their Peak alltime greatest
Peak how great Mr Trump and Mr Modi
dancing hand in hand that good that's
that's what I think is going to happen
is it a good thing for India we'll see
but
yeah okay
next oie and crack says compare US
military to Russian one I know you won't
admit it but the US military is 10 times
stronger than Russian
military okay so this person believes
that uh I don't I'm biased of some in
some way I'm biased oh absolutely I'm
biased towards India but I don't deny
the facts whatever the facts are so
let's find out what the facts are let's
compare the US military to the Russian
one so first of all Let's uh Google top
Air Forces top Air Forces okay let let
let's put that on the screen uh top Air
Forces
so let's let's go to the world directory
of modern military aircraft WD MMA
whatever it
is global air powers ranking 2025 what
is the thing like okay the top 10 number
one is the US Air Force 5,4 units number
two is the US Navy 2,500 units number
three is the Russian Air Force 3,600
something units number four is the US
Army number five is the US Marines good
God and they're ranking India as number
six and China as number seven I'm not
sure why but whatever I'm not looking
into that let's look at the top row this
is also interesting but let's look at
the top row Russia is number three and
the other four top four are US military
divisions so you can see that if you add
these numbers up 5,000 plus 2,5 7,500
plus 11,000 almost 12,000 almost 13,000
units the Americans have and the
Russians have 3,600 the russan s can't
match they don't send a chance against
the US Air Force clearly okay that's
number one uh let's see military
spending by country let us see military
spending by country that's a good
indicator of how powerful a nation is
military spending my country let's go to
statista countries with the highest
military spending in the world 2023 us
916 billion dollar nearly a
trillion China 296 billion Russia Ria
109 and India 83.6 the top four okay uh
France doesn't even figure anywhere
nearby so once again the US military
spending is about roughly almost nine
times that of Russia almost nine times
definitely over eight times okay so
there again clearly the US is more
powerful way more powerful now let's see
uh nuclear weapons uh nuclear weapon
strength uh let's do this so we go to I
can for this
what do we have uh there are total 12,
512 allegedly Warheads in the world
Russia has 5889 Warheads the US is 5224
China 410 and so on so forth so and so
forth okay so in this matter Russia is
slightly ahead of the US but if you look
at everything else the US is way way way
ahead of
Russia
right so how do We compare these two
Nations so look we have to do a hard
power comparison hard power is not just
military strength it's also economic
strength it's also various other factors
okay I'll not go into all of that but if
you do a basic hard power comparison
which includes uh the the the area land
area of a Nation the population of a
Nation the kind of resources the nation
has the economic the GDP of the nation
the military expenditure of the nation
the nuclear warhe number of nuclear
warheads you do all of that uh how
Sovereign the nation is how uh energy
independent or not it is and various
other factors you put all of that
together into into uh into a formula
that makes sense then you will find that
you can calculate the hard power score
of a Nation as a number and if you do
that you will see that the US has about
twice the hard power of Russia and the
US military strength probably is around
10 times that of Russia so if the US
military strength is 10 times that of
Russia and the US has way more power
position than Russia then why is the
hard power only twice that of Russia for
that you have to understand how hard
power is calculated but the but the most
important factor is
this the US doesn't cannot even dare
start a war against Russia for simply
one
factor a war with Russia will mean the
end of the world in the complete
annihilation of the US and Russia also
because of the nuclear might that Russia
has and Russia has the best Delivery
Systems Rockets
icbms
so there's no question there's no
question of starting a war with Russia
even though the US military may be 10
times more powerful there they still
don't dare fight
Russia and so it's like that you see uh
so you have to look at the world through
a nuanced perspect
perspective the US may have 10 times the
mil military might as Russia but the
Russians have the most devastating
nuclear Arsenal in the world and the
Americans cannot dare fight Russia
because of this and there are other
factors as well so look at the world
from a not a black and white one or zero
perspective but from a more nuanced
perspective oie and crack I would
recommend doing that you know you will
you will learn a lot more than trying to
taunt somebody
making fun you know learn
something okay PR Paul and Sam ask this
question Rubio US Secretary of State
Marco Rubio has recently has openly
admitted that that the Ukraine war is a
US Russia proxy conflict and this isn't
surprising it's exactly what I have been
saying since February 24 2022 but why
are they being so blatant and open about
this now has the US ever made such
admissions before what's the bigger game
at Play soat says Marco Rubio recently
stated the Ukraine conflict is a proxy
war between two nuclear Powers with the
US aiding R Ukraine against Russia at
the same time the era of us unipolar
dominance seems to be shifting with
Donald Trump's policies accelerating the
emergence of uni of a multipolar world
what would the US benefit from this
transition and if multipolarity fully
takes shape how can the US ensure it's
not dethroned from its position as the
world's leading superpower or only
superpower sole superpower so yes um
it's it's rather unusual that the US
Secretary of State admits that they have
been engaged in a proxy war against
Russia Ukraine is nothing but a proxy
war it's apparently it's fashionable to
say this now I have been saying this for
the past three years when it was not
fashionable to say that uh it's a proxy
war so yes what I've been saying has
been
confirmed uh by the US Secretary of
State uh so why are they being open
about this now it's because they want to
end the war the the Trump Administration
wants to end the war immediately they
don't want to waste any more American
resources money Manpower material
whatever not Manpower but material Etc
in the war it's a waste of their it's a
drain on their resources so they want to
end it
immediately so they're going to put the
blame on the previous administration the
Biden Harris Administration Trump has
been saying this war would have never
happened if I was president and probably
is right so he's putting the blame on
the previous administration and he
saying that they were engaged in they
had engaged the US in a proxy war
against Russia and Ukraine has been
destroyed as a result and we want to end
this war so that's why they are saying
it openly now I'm not sure if they've
made such admissions before uh but yeah
the bigger g game is that the US wants
to focus on other things especially
China and so on um and they want to
focus on Europe as well in a different
way so uh that's that's the answer to PR
Paul's question now uh is the era of us
unipolar dominance shifting is it ending
I don't think it's it's ending it's the
sole superpower but Trump's policies are
indeed emerge accelerating the the very
rapid geopolitical change in the world
is it a unipolar world I'm not sure
about that what would a unipolar world
look like ask yourselves my friends what
would a unipolar world look
like in my opinion a unipolar world is
about 20 30 nations with nuclear powers
that sorry that's a multipolar world ask
ask yourself the question what would a
multipolar world look like in my opinion
a multi-polar world would have 2030
nations with nuclear Powers with nuclear
weapons we don't want that uh
anyway what does the US benefit from
this transition is the question right uh
See by ending the war this huge drain on
on the US economy
ends and uh it also brings Russia
eventually back into the Western economy
by uh ending some of the sanctions and
so on it also uh ends Russia's very
close dependence on China it gives
Russia more
options um and so so that's the deal
with Russia and China now why is Trump
uh making statements about leaving NATO
Etc and and and uh putting a lot of
blame on the EU Nations for not paying
enough money for the upkeep of NATO and
all that Trump wants to put the European
nations in their place and he wants to
extract more money out of them for NATO
and he's going to get it done see the in
the 20th century the European powers
were treated like royalty even though
they were no longer world powers at all
but they the US had a policy of treating
them like royalty treating them like
they very they
equals and managing them in that manner
Trump doesn't believe in any of that
Trump is is like an elephant in a
library he like a it's like a Wildfire
raging through a library he's as
restrained as that he's not going to
give anybody any of that
unnecessary um respect and all that
everybody needs to get in line and it's
going to be a very transactional world
and he's going to get Europe to do what
he wants right now the European
nations the EU leaders the bureaucrats
are all ganging up against the US and
they're they're claiming that they will
support zinski they don't have the
resources resources to support zinski
they don't have the money or the weapons
or the ammunition of what whatever to
support zinski and keep the Ukraine war
going um so they're going to find out
very soon what the world really is like
and they are
insignificant these nations are
insignificant what can Lithuania give to
Ukraine what can Luxembourg give to to
Ukraine what can the UK give to Ukraine
maybe a billion pounds two billion
billion pounds and then what after that
what um so Trump is goingon
to um show the European nations where
they actually belong in the World Order
much lower than other nations Nations
like India actually geopolitically the
European nations EU Nations and NATO
nations are insignificant without us
backing they are not even in the same
league as as as a smaller power like
India so Trump is going to do that and
he's going to keep the European nations
under a tight leash eventually they're
going to remain in NATO they're going to
do whatever the Americans tell them
maybe the Americans leave NATO or leave
or whatever going to still control the
European nations so uh that's the kind
of world we're going to see in the next
3 four years a lot of change is going to
happen what the US benefits is they they
get more direct control over the assets
they own what are the assets they own
they own the EU they own NATO they own a
lot lot of Africa we not looking even
there even right they own South Korea
they own Japan they own
Taiwan they own Pakistan and east and
west Pakistan and and a lot more so
they're going to have much more direct
control over everything for the upcoming
rivalry with China see uh they they are
afraid of Russia because of Russia's
incredible nuclear might but beyond that
Russia isn't that
strong but when it comes to China China
is a genuine rival to the US
technologically China's military might
is untested the last war they fought was
in 1979 and they lost the war but this
is a whole different China they're the
world's largest Navy and they are the
only nation that is in competition with
the US in various Technologies including
AI so that is what the US really needs
to focus on on on containing China and
denying China the opportunity to
grow so for that to happen you need to
take much stronger control over all the
resources you own so that's what is
happening right now the us is going to
is to and the US is doing all this to
ensure it's not dethroned from its
position as the world's superpow so it's
a work in progress we're going to keep
an eye on this and uh yeah that that's
the direction in which the world is
going okay prai says with Trump openly
criticizing zinsky and Europe
acknowledging its dependence on the US
is Western support for Ukraine starting
to Vain not now even Elon Musk suggests
offering zilinsky amnesty for a peaceful
transition is Ukraine being set up for a
geopolitical reset does it what does it
mean for zelinsky's fate and what could
be Ukraine's future after numerous
European leaders publicly hosted in
voice support for zinski has anything
changed on the ground since that spat at
the the White House last week so the LA
last week we had zin's visit to the
White House in which he behaved
extremely ungraciously he went there as
a as a supplicant as a
beggar but he is so full of himself
because of the way the media has
lionized him and the European leaders
have lionized him that he did not
realize he thought that he could do the
same thing in the US and Trump is a
different kind of person so they don't
work with
Trump uh and zinsky I believe you know
he deserved the treatment he got now the
deal is that uh he left the White House
he left the US he went back to Europe
and all various EU leaders hosted him
and once again lionized him King Charles
of England hosted him and gave him a lot
of honor and all the EU bureaucrats
leaders so-called leaders they tweeted
the same message in support of Ukraine
and zinsky essentially zilinsky that we
support zinsky that sort of thing and
they're all saying and and M M of France
is saying that the Ukraine war cannot
end it cannot end with Russia keeping
the territories it has it has you know
conquered and we're going to support
Ukraine and so on the question is does
the EU collectively have sufficient
resources to keep the Ukraine war
going um essentially you have two
options right if you you cannot just
keep the war going and keep people dying
and bleeding
you either end the war or you pour
enough resources into the Ukrainian
military that can defeat Russia you
can't just keep it going month after
month year after year does it make any
sense it's Madness who's dying
ukrainians are dying and Russians but
they don't care about the Russians so
let's talk about the ukrainians
ukrainians are dying every day fighting
the
Russians so either put enough resources
into the military might of Ukraine that
can defeat Russia or end the godamn war
don't just keep it going forever it's
it's destroying Ukraine does it make any
sense what I'm saying to
you so these European leaders they they
they they they they don't like Trump
they don't like the way Trump deals with
them because he doesn't respect them he
doesn't give them any respect he do he
doesn't show them any respect he's
treating them the way he would treat an
African leader
because you know from a hard power
perspective that's where they are they
are not the EU nations are not sovereign
Nations they have no military might then
they have small economies in in
recession and these are ins significant
Nations and Trump sees it that way only
that's why these people don't like him
uh so what's going to happen now what's
going to happen is that the EU na EU
leaders will will have discovered by now
that they cannot keep the war going on
and Trump has now put a freeze to the US
supply of money and everything else to
Ukraine so no more us Aid let's see how
long the EU can keep this going maybe a
month or two at most and then they will
also stop because they cannot you know
they don't have V economies they don't
have these big factories that produce on
you know on a continuous basis huge
amounts of arms and ammunition they they
don't have any of that they don't even
have sufficient money to uh keep their
people warm sometimes during
winter so what happens now is the
question is that's the question they can
keep lionizing zalinsky Etc what's going
to happen now is in a month or two
everybody is going to calm down and and
and confront reality okay that's that's
what will happen and then uh zin's fate
will be decided probably he will be
moved to some European nation maybe to P
maybe zinski can move to Paris he is not
going to be welcome in the US anymore
but uh I think he will be allowed to to
make a reasonably dignified exit out of
Ukraine he'll probably go to Paris or or
or some other place U somewhere in the
EU maybe he can set up home with Kaya
kalas or whoever you know there people
who who support him so much so he's
going to go to some European nation and
somebody else will be placed in the
position of interim president of the of
Ukraine and they will sign this deal
with Trump the minerals deal the US gets
access to all ownership of all the
minerals of Ukraine the mineral wealth
and then the US and Russia Trump and
Putin will meet and they will work out
the framework of the ceasefire and then
the Ukraine war will end that's what's
going to happen Europe is going to be
shown its place by Trump not by Putin by
Trump so by doing this the war ends
Trump can tell his population his
constituency his voters that see I ended
the war I ended this waste War we were
wasting so much us tax money it's over
is going to put ukra put Europe in its
place if need they can if needed they
can do regime changes in various nations
in Europe they can do it the Americans
and by the time the four years of trump
are out they're going to have complete
hard control over
Europe so that's what is going to happen
I'm actually making predictions here and
let's see come back here in in four
years and let's see how this turns out
aha okay
Bor
boru boruto boruto says what do you
think about the situation of Bangladesh
and cukil land so-called Kil land as
many terrorist groups have captured
massive amounts of land in Bangladesh
and Myanmar and are now join wanting to
join India and they're also giving us
the complete access of the lands do you
think we should accept it and there's
more questions about the same thing
uh geopolitical dub says is zoland by
grabbing myanmar's land really within
Barat how do you see the current
situation of Myanmar namata says please
give your opinion on the India India
Myanmar merger is it good or bad for
India Sunil says one miso MP asked chin
Rebels to join India will we anex some
territory if this happens prai says
what's your take on the mizoram MP's
visit to a rebel outfit in Myanmar
urging G them to join the Indian
Union with Myanmar Rebel units merging
in mizoram and the home Ministry
ensuring free movement in Manipur could
this indicate a shift towards long-term
stability in the Northeast uh and
broader whatever how significant is this
in India's broader geopolitical and
internal security
strategy okay okay okay okay a lot of
questions about and there there are more
I just I was able to just take three
four five of these questions so
apparently some news has come
out okay let's put the news on the
screen shall we mizoram MPS visiting
uh Rebel outfits in Burma and all let's
let's put this on the screen there are
multiple pieces of news that are coming
out let's see this is from the
Hindu mizoram MP visits Rebel outfit in
Myanmar asks them to join the Indian
Union miso National front MP crosses to
Myanmar on foot meets chinland Council
to forge friendship and Brotherhood
saying that they belong to the same miso
family and we'll brief home Ministry
external Affairs ministers on the talks
and there some picture of this uh and he
this this MP has visited this camp and
offices of this Insurgent
Group which controls uh parts of
Northwest Myanmar in areas bordering
India he says he has invited them to
join the union of India and there is as
there is no official government in
Myanmar because there is a shared tribal
Bond on both sides of the border which
is a cookie Bond The Zo people born
right so uh that's the kind of news
that's coming out now first of all I
don't trust these news outlets that
report all of this I don't trust these
reporters first of all I don't know what
the truth is on the ground in in Myanmar
okay and if some uh
MP Member of Parliament who is a miso
person zo zi person uh crosses over into
the neighboring country and tells an
Insurgent out outfit or whatever you
want to call them that you need to join
the union of India because you are we
are the same
ethnicity ask yourself this question on
what basis is he inviting them to join
India on the basis of common culture and
civilization with India or on the basis
of the same cookie ethnicity cookie mizo
ethnicity
right now the we know that there is this
entire project that the Biden
Administration started cookie land for
Christ right they have been funding this
and these people have been terrorizing
Indians in
Manipur doing all kinds of horrific
atrocities do we want such people to
become Indians uh don't we have enough
lacks of of illegal INF infiltrators
Foreigner cookies squatting on over half
of Manipur do we want even more just
because we'll get some few square
kilometers of territory I am okay with
territory manipur's Cabo Valley is
Indian I don't know it has never
technically officially become Burmese we
can take that back the question is look
if you want to take parts of
Burma the question is that is fine but
you to remember that Burma as a large
entity as an overall entity is is is a
Buddhist Hindu Buddhist Nation right and
if
we and these cookies who are fighting
the Burmese
government they don't have allegiance to
Burma so it's almost like stealing your
neighbor territory because
anti-nationals are occupying the
territory in the long run do you think
the people of Burma will like what we do
if this happens just for a little bit of
territory I am I would be happy if the
people of
Burma decide
voluntarily to you reunite with India
after a national referendum or something
that's the right way to do it nibbling
away little pieces of territor is
behaving like China has been behaving in
the past against India because there is
a civil war in your country and your
government is no longer able to to able
to uh exercise control on some
territories will steal them now because
the anti-nationals of Burma have the
same ethnicity as the cookies of who are
occupying Manipur do you think it's the
right thing to do is it think it's a
viable strategy long- term do these
people have any
civilizational or or or cultural connect
with India no they are the they
they sometimes claim they are Christians
they sometimes claim they are Jews and
they're killing Hindus in man in Manipur
do you want such people to become part
of IND don't we have enough of those
already illegally occupying half more
than half of
Manipur and who authorized this miso MP
to cross over IL legally into another
country into the neighboring country and
ask the so-called Rebels or whatever to
join India who authorized him to do
this so I think India needs to be really
careful in this matter okay this cookie
land for Christ project has been
bleeding Indians since uh May
2023 these people who are fighting India
trying to create an artificial Christian
Nation out of parts of India Burma and
and and Bangladesh and shik H spoke
about this by while she was still in
power do you think you can trust them
they are on the payroll of a foreign
country they are on the payroll of the
enemies the civilizational enemies of
India okay do you want more of them in
India so these people are Internationals
not just for India but also for Burma
they don't even have allegiance to Burma
they're fighting the burmes
government uh I I would say that we need
to be really careful about this Indians
are Overjoyed when we think of you know
India gaining some
territory if we want to gain territory
we have to gain it where it really
matters which is po Gil baltistan aiin
and so on those are the territories we
have lost in
Wars but if we steal burm territory in
this underhanded manner we are not
different from China or
Pakistan so if if India wants bur's
territory it has to be done properly end
the Civil War in Burma whenever that
happens let there be a proper go
government that that administers the
whole of Burma then let there be a
referendum in Burma and if they choose
to reunite with India I'll be the
happiest person in the world but this is
not the way to do it to join hand to to
join hands with the anti-nationals of
Burma who are Al also fighting and
killing
Indians uh I hope the government of
India is not involved in in this entire
matter I hope this MP is acting on his
own but uh I I I would really urge a
great amount of caution and Indians we
Indians need to be very cautious about
whom we support just because there's the
prospect that maybe India may get some
territory a few square kilometers here
and there please look at the big picture
look at look at the world from a
longterm perspective we don't want these
people in India we have enough of them
already we have more than 100,000 sorry
we have more than 100 million illegals
in India squatting on our land all
across the
country Bangladesh ringas cookies God
knows what else do we need more of these
people who hold guns in their hands and
shoot shoot at civilians do we want more
of these
people so yeah that's the way I see
it suria says if the UK attempts to
obstruct the peace deal by sending its
forces to Ukraine
will the US likely ignite the Scottish
and Irish Independence
movements so yeah the UK is is saying
that you know starmer that guy Kier
starmer the the current temporary prime
minister of the UK he met with zelinski
right after zalinski left the US and in
right after his disastrous meeting with
Trump and he met zinski and received him
very warmly and said that the UK will
support the the zinsky regime and uh
ensure the war
continues so let's say Kier starmer puts
his money where his mouth is and and
sends money to Ukraine and let's say
even send soldiers to
Ukraine what happens
then the Russians will annihilate those
soldiers they will launch air strikes
and missile strikes and wipe out those
soldiers before they can even uh you
know change their clothes Russians will
do that uh but the bigger problem is if
the if the if the British government
goes against the US in this
manner then uh
Trump what can Trump do will will will
the Trump regime U reignite the these
Independence
movements it sounds
farfetched but understand the historical
context forget the Scottish independence
movement when it comes to the Irish
Independence Movement for for the most
part for the majority of the 20th
century there was this long drawn out
and pretty
intense Irish Independence struggle
against the British occupiers of
Ireland and in the UK it's called the
troubles and you had Irish Irish
resistance fighting British soldiers on
the streets of Ireland and the British
soldiers committed all kinds of
atrocities and massacres against the
Irish
so the Irish hate the
British and this Insurgency went on for
decades and decades and in the 80s they
almost took out Margaret Thatcher they
they uh lobbed they launched a mortar
Shell at the hotel room where she was
staying and she just happened to be in a
different room at at the time that's why
she survived so this went on for a very
long time okay now Margaret T was a very
independent lady you you can say
whatever you want about her about her
policies but as long as she was the
Prime Minister the UK the UK was a
Sovereign Nation it may have been no
longer a first R world power but it was
Sovereign it did not tow the American
line okay the moment so
after she stepped down or or or after
she ended her her her political career
the next prime minister was uh John
Major
and under John Major also the UK was
reasonably a Sovereign Nation after John
Major you have the Advent of Mr Tony
Blair as prime minister of the UK and it
is at that point in
time with the uh Prime ministership of
Tony Blair that the UK
becomes a US lap dog the UK was no
longer Sovereign from that moment on so
people have called Mr Tony Blair an
American poodle okay not a very nice
thing to say but it is what it
is and once to Blair comes to
power low end behold the Irish
Insurgency
ends
yeah just like that like like
magic the moment you have a prime
minister in office who turns his country
into a us vasal immediately the Irish
Insurgency
ended so you can I suppose put two and
together right you can so yeah um so if
Kier
starmer goes against us interests what
could the Americans do will they
reignite the Irish Insurgency Freedom
struggle and maybe the Scottish Freedom
struggle William Wallace Freedom Give Me
Freedom or give me death all the stuff
no they don't need to do that they don't
need to take such drastic measures all
they need to do the Americans
is is is is regime change get rid of
starmer you know there's a political
coup in the in the in the in the
political party and he's they all his
his MPS no longer have confidence in him
in the withdraw support and some new
leader some new puppet leader comes up
that's all that needs to be done you
don't need to start to reignite an
independence movement if the UK is not
behaving just get rid of that prime
minister okay give him a slap on the
wrist put him back into the back back
benches of the parliament and have a new
new puppet leader in his place that's
all the U us needs to do so yeah starmar
is acting up right now but it won't last
long okay Vikram Ador says there was a
security breach in Dr J Shankar's
security God forbid if anything so it's
an incident that happened in the UK Mr
Dr Jer was in the UK and this security
breach happened when he was leaving some
some place after uh official event so if
anything dangerous happened what would
be the repercussions U it's time India
takes security of not just ministers but
higher ranking and high ranking
officials but normal citizens as well
and teach the radical elements and those
supporting them a lesson what are My
Views samat says with the US with the UK
pushing for a free trade agreement with
India since 2022 how will the recent
khalistani attack on Indian external
affairs minister Dr SJ Shanker and
ongoing security lapses impact the FDA
negotiations
despite urgently needing the deal UK
police stood idle until a man stepped in
front of Dr Jan's car holding the Indian
flag forcing action given past incidents
like the April 2023 attack on the Indian
High commission and various riots
against Hindus and and Indian origin
people in the UK could these escalating
tensions further delay or jeopardize the
FDA okay yeah so this thing happened and
Dr J Shankar's Convoy was kind of
attacked and this was a very very
serious ious and significant security
lap security breach and the UK police
just stood and let this
happen so I don't know what the the
conversation was that Dr jashar had with
whoever did it go well did it not go
well uh maybe the UK is being very
demanding and Dr J Shankar and his team
were probably not uh not giving into
their demands perhaps I mean you know we
are a superior country bigger more
powerful country more important country
you don't get to make demands to us we
need yeah sure let's have a a free trade
agreement but it has to be Equitable and
it has to be a win-win situation and it
has to uh be good for both sides
beneficial mutually beneficial you can't
get away with your demands we're not
going to give in so maybe that sort of
thing may have happened I'm just
guessing I wasn't there
okay and maybe the UK and look the UK
has always had this attitude towards
India that we were your colonizers we
were your occupiers we destroyed your
civilization and we are super Superior
Nation you are a defeated nation and we
are a superior race all that all that
all that nonsense right they always have
had this attitude whether it's the UK
government or UK politicians or even
common people in the UK not all but many
of them have this attitude even today
that they are superior to
us and they in the west the anglosphere
the five eyes Nations the UK the US
Canada Australia and New Zealand we know
that they have been
harboring anti-india terrorists on their
soil there's plenty plenty of anti-india
terrorists and and known terrorists and
criminals who uh live in the UK and
Canada The Killers of shik mujibur
Rahman I I believe some of them live in
the UK I mean ass Assassins right so
that's the kind of nation it is and the
Americans also they're harboring gur
patan sing panu some some such clown you
know khalistani terrorist uh the
Canadians Harbor lots of khalistani
elements these five nations the five
eyes Nations they Harbor lots of
anti-india forces and they deploy them
whenever required whenever they want to
send a message to
India um and there's been passed such
actions in Canada attacks on on Indian
uh
properties indan Government properties
calls for ass assassinating Indian
officials uh celebrating the
assassination of prime minister Indira
ghi and in the UK there have been riots
against Indians of against Indian origin
people especially against Hindus attack
on the Indian High commission this is
this all these incidents are not
isolated they are all
coordinated okay so my point is yeah
sure I'm okay with a Free Trade
Agreement as long as it is beneficial to
India I don't care about it whether it's
beneficial to the UK or not it should be
beneficial to India India is more
important than the UK India is a more
important Nation than the UK so from my
perspect perspective if they are
behaving like this then they need to be
sent a message they need to be taught a
lesson
um and the government of India should
take appropriate measures to respond to
this this cannot keep on
happening uh but yeah it's serious and
these people need to be put in their
place okay Sumer okay lots of questions
from Sumer today uh Donald Trump
recently questioned the US Japan
Alliance sparking speculation about its
potential collapse if this were to
happen though just in the realm of Realm
of speculation how might it impact
Japan's strategic position after Japan's
failed Asian NATO bid with India in 2024
it shifted to aiding India's Vision 2047
economically what could be the
implications for India's security and
economy and how might China react
especially as you previously mentioned
Japan could very easily and quickly
develop nuclear weapons okay so let's
look at the background behind this
matter and uh it all goes down to what
Trump has been saying he's not happy
with uh with with uh Japanese uh he's
not he's dissatisfied with how things
are with Japan so let's put that on the
screen
quickly um what what the background is
what the context is so this is a tweet
by a a Japanese person Trump voices
dissatisfaction with the Japan us
Alliance says that the US is obligated
to protect Japan but Japan has no
obligation to protect the US under any
circumstances and this is obviously not
a satisfactory Arrangement according to
president Donald Trump of the US so look
let me just point out respectfully to
Shri Donald Trump G that the US is
obligated to protect Japan because the
US militarily occupies
Japan and the US doesn't have more than
120 military bases permanently on
Japanese soil to protect Japan it has
this for its own purposes and its own
benefit it militarily occupies Japan and
therefore it is obligated to protect
Japan as the occupying
power but of course Donald Trump wants
to wants to have a win everywhere he
needs to have a better deal everywhere
so he's voicing dissatisfaction with the
Japan us Alliance and says that Japan
also needs to protect the US in some way
so that brings me back to what Henry
kinger has had predicted the year he
died just a few months before he died
and it was
this so Kissinger one of the greatest
diplomats not the nicest persons but one
of the greatest and most important
diplomats in the world he said in 2023
just a a few months before it died the
Japan is heading towards becoming a
nuclear power in 5 years okay he made
that prediction and he you have to take
kinger seriously you may not like him
but you have to take him seriously so if
you see what he predicted in the light
of what Donald Trump is saying you have
to ask yourself how in the world can a
nation like Japan that is under US
military occupation since
1945 how can such a nation protect the
US and from my
perspective one of the simplest
straightforward ways is for Japan to
become a nuclear power and Japan can
have nuclear weapons next week if they
want to that's how technologically
advanced they are it's just that they're
not allowed to so all Trump has to do is
allow them to acquire nukes and by by
the next by the end of the year they may
have an arsenal of 20 30 40 50 Warheads
they may have
it and that way they could protect the
US by being a much stronger line of
defense against
China so do you think my friends my
viewers do you think that Japan could
have
nukes could become a nuclear power in
the next couple of years let me know
what you think I think Kissinger's
prediction may be on
the Japan may be on the path to uh
making his prediction come true it's
possible Bill Williams says can you us
new posturing towards the Russian
Federation it cannot be deciphered as an
attempt to remove all close
relationships of China in order to
isolate China in the event of a hot war
between the US and China in the current
geopolitical world or Taiwan for example
will Russia stay neutral or just
passively pass some sanctions or
completely side with the us if the US
does promit a l a lot of ease of
restrictions on
Russia good question so everything
that's happening is is in preparation
for the showdown between the US and
China the US sees China as the major
long-term technological rival Russia is
a very powerful nation that the US fears
only for the nuclear Arsenal Arsenal
that the Russians have but as we know
President Putin has always sought better
relations with the US Mr Putin in his
early years as president even naively
thought that Russia could should become
a part of NATO so Putin has always
wanted peace with the West with the US
so if you give him that he's going to be
happy of course now he's a much older
much wiser man and he sees the world the
way it really is now okay uh so let's
say the Ukraine war and ends in the US
and Russia they strike a good deal which
is beneficial for both sides and the US
drops a lot of sanctions that they are
currently uh they currently imposed on
Russia and they reintegrate integrate
Russia with into the Western econom
economy um enable Swift again and so on
what does it mean it means Russia a lot
of pressure goes of Russia and Russia
becomes a much happier Nation overall
and Russia's dependence very strong
dependence on China also eases up a
lot so that's Obviously good for Russia
now let's say once this happens the
Americans uh impose sanctions on China
and and start a trade War even further
trade war with China and let's say then
there's a war or Taiwan or whatsoever
what happens now so what does Russia
what should Russia do from a Russian
perspective not from my perspective not
from your perspective from a Russian
perspective what is in Russia's best
interests so let's say hypothetically
Russia
sits stays away doesn't participate
doesn't do anything in the war and the
US and Russia and China go to war Russia
stays out of it and the US defeats China
then what happens
then Russia is totally
isolated so it's not good for Russia if
China is destroyed or defeated by the
Americans Russia needs a multi-polar
world with China and India playing their
own roles in this so it's not good for
Russia if China is defeated by the us
then the US can completely focus on the
destruction of
Russia so it doesn't make sense from a
Russian perspective to stay neutral and
passive if there's a war between the US
and China I believe Russia will support
China if there is a hot war between the
US and China and Russia will act as the
security guaran of China from a nuclear
perspective that's how I see things
happening and obviously the Americans
and Chinese will not go to war it's
stupid to go to war but there's going to
be a whole new phase of geopolitics now
which is going to be the strategy of
denial this book so the Americans will
seek to deny the world's economy to
China and the world's technology to
China and China will be under meure to
independently match the US
technologically and maybe maybe surpass
the US technologically especially in the
in the in the realm of AI artificial
intelligence both machine learning and
all of that so it's going to be a very
very intense tussle which is coming up
this decade and Russia will not stay
neutral Russia will be
happy uh to have a good relationship
with the with the us but Russia needs
China to remain in the position that it
is today
and Russia is obviously happy that there
are frictions between China and the us
because otherwise China becomes too
powerful so Russia wants neither China
to be too powerful or the US to be too
powerful Russia is Happy the way things
are right now it wants some adjustment
reignment it wants the Ukraine war to
end it wants to be reintegrated into the
Western economy but it will not
take the the US's side against China it
will in in the event of a war okay very
complicated scenario but it is not in
Russia's interests to see China defeated
by the
US kushagra Kalashnikov says what's the
next step after the US creates and
unleashes Asi will the Americans form a
world government what is Russia China
and India's next move and why aren't
these Powers putting out all of their
resources into eii if it's that much of
a GameChanger or would it be best for us
to just give up at this point
okay ASI artificial super intelligence
let me just remind everybody what these
terms mean what does AGI mean what does
ASI mean in the context of artificial
intelligence now everybody knows that
there is something called artificial
intelligence in the world um you have
all these
programs what all these companies open
AI uh anthropic and the Deep seek and
and what not the French have something
called M so all these companies have
produced AI systems pretty powerful ones
and very useful ones and these are
available at a charge for a monthly
charge to viewers and you can use them
for whatever purpose some are image
generators some can generate uh videos
some can generate music most of them are
text text based things that that will
output text based on whatever Trump you
give them and so on you can see over the
over the past couple of years how
increasingly sophisticated these systems
are
becoming so what in the context of all
this what is Agi what is artificial
general intelligence AGI AGI is an AI
system artificially intelligent system
that has a human equivalent 130 IQ which
has the equivalent of a human with 130
IQ so I think the average IQ in the
world must be in the
90s uh in some countries like Eastern
Asia Etc the average IQ is around one 5
110 I think if you have an IQ of 100 you
are a reasonably fun well functioning
human being if you have IQ 120 you are
pretty intelligent 130 is very
intelligent I think 150 plus is genius
level so 130 is if a if a person has
iq30 that's a pretty intelligent person
really like Elite level intelligence
maybe top 10% or something I'm I'm not
sure exactly what but that probably top
10% so if an i AI system has that sort
of IQ that's what we call AGI artificial
general intelligence obviously that's
not all it is it has to
be it has to have human like
characteristics and other things but for
the sake of oversimplifying things let's
call an AGI system a system with the
same IQ as a 130 IQ human same abilities
as a 130 IQ human what is ASI artificial
super
intelligence ASI is an AI system whose
intelligence is equal to a human with
300 or 500 IQ and such humans don't
exist that is super human
intelligence so so an ASI system
artificially super intelligent system is
the natural progression of what happens
after a system becomes
AI it can start iteratively improving
itself and becoming more and more
intelligent and capable and eventually
you have ASI artificial super
intelligence and Asi system will be able
to develop and devise
Technologies and scientific
breakthroughs that can only exist in the
realm of science fiction or magic today
so once a
country develops an ASI system that
country can very rapidly develop ma
magic like Technologies technologies
that will look like magic to
you okay they'll be able to have
incredibly Advan propulsion
systems they'll be able to have aircraft
that travel 20 times the speed of sound
they'll be able to uh colonize Moon next
week if they want they'll be able to
have people on Mars by uh next quarter
they'll be able to have nuclear
fusion in a glass okay on a at room
temperature
they'll they these systems will devise
Technologies and and substances you
can't even imagine today and such a
nation will very rapidly put a huge gap
between itself and everybody
else and if they play their cards right
they will be able to ensure that no
other Nation can ever catch
up and they will have the Technologies
to remotely prevent other nations from
developing such
Technologies so when you develop ASI you
don't unleash it you keep it secret but
you unleash it in in secret
so you will have UFO like Technologies
and everything you have seen in science
fiction and Magic so that's what ASI is
and that's why AI is is the biggest arms
race right now so the Chinese are very
much in the race yes uh their their deep
seek systems are supposed to be even
probably better than most of the a open
AI systems and so on and clothe
apparently 3.7 or whatever is
exceptional perhaps in coding and
whatnot so um the US and China are neck
to neck right now the French are kind of
in The Fray with their M system and the
Indian government has said that by the
end of this year we will have our own
large language model wonderful what you
going to do with it why do you want
it do you want it just because everybody
has one so I also should have one India
has always had the attitude of of you
know doing something that people did 20
years ago we should do it
now and in the the AI world 6 months is
like 20
years or two years is like 20 years so I
think India needs to really really put a
lot of effort into this the indan
government has the resources to to to
has all the resources the money and
Manpower and Brilliant students and
Brilliant kids everything we have we
just need focused effort and Leadership
so India could catch up you know in the
next two years with these nations we
could I'm not sure what Russia's deal is
maybe they are doing things in secret
they have been denied technology by the
US chips uh gpus and whatnot even the
Chinese but the Chinese are making their
own chips and they're making do with
chips that are not bleeding
edge um yeah so if India starts becoming
an air power they will also face
sanctions like the Chinese are facing
okay don't don't worry that will happen
but that that shows that you arve on the
big stage uh so it's it's going to be
see the AI race is going to determine
who rules the world for the next 10,000
years it's that big of a
deal most people don't see how big of a
deal it is but it is that big of a
deal uh and once a nation has
ASI they're going to very rapidly in a
couple of months put a huge gap between
them and everybody else and they'll be
unbeatable and they'll actively use
their technological advances to deny any
other Nation from progressing
now when you have that sort of power why
would you want to form a One World
Government why not just take over the
world and look to to govern other
nations takes a lot of effort AI can do
it I'm sure when you have ASI but
instead of instead of having
U having physical occupation of Nations
and all you can just vassalize them and
and that sort of thing but yeah it will
be some form of world government so
whichever Nation develops ASI technology
will be the ruler of the world for the
probably the next 1,000 years if they
are able to deny everybody else uh
prevent other nations from Gaining such
technology and then they will rule the
world in some form or other so it will
be one nation that rules the whole world
which you can call a one world a world
government so that's the big Stakes
that's the huge uh race that's that's on
right now it's the 21st century version
of the 20th century Cold War War arms
race and uh the winner will
be apparent in the next 2 three years
next two three years we'll know who's
going to rule the world for the next
10,000
years sh Kar says did the kfat movement
actually have an impact over India's
Freedom struggle or was it just another
publicity stunt by Mr Gandhi was the
movement really necessary and did it
actually unite Indians
okay okay okay a question about history
the kilat movement what was this kilat
movement it was a
movement to restore the Islamic
calipat the califit is an institution in
Islam and whoever is the khif the khif
Khalifa whatever they call it is the
ruler of all Muslims
worldwide historic it's been that way so
you've had various calipat in the past
the umay khalifat and the rashidun
khalifat and uh various other caliphates
and uh eventually the ottoman caliphate
which was the last great
caliphate uh so the calips have ruled
from Bagdad they've ruled from Kao
they've ruled from Mecca or medina one
of these two cities and eventually from
Constantinople
Istanbul right so
ever since the Ottoman Empire became a
major Force the ottoman Emperor whoever
it was declared himself to be the Khalif
and then this institution continued with
the ottoman ottoman sultanate so whoever
was the Ottoman king after whichever one
was was the person who started this
whoever was the Ottoman Emperor would
also be called the khif and the calipat
was based out of
Constantinople now in the early 20th
century
the Ottoman Empire was on its last legs
it had become an extremely corrupt and
and and Powerless uh institution the uh
the khalif's power was limited just to
his his his Palace and his Haram
essentially and in the 1920s or
somewhere I think 21 22 or maybe 1919
after the end of the second world war U
or when the world war was first world
war and when the first world war is
ending the great uh
Turkish General Mustafa kimal atat
announced his U intention to abolish the
califit to abolish the institution of
the
khif and after the Turkish war of
independence Mustafa kamalat actually
abolished the khalifat and he expelled
the last ottoman Emperor and Khalif out
of
turkey and today the the the descendants
of the Ottoman Emperors they live in the
US and other countries in the West
okay so Mustafa Kamal Ataturk the
Turkish dictator who then became the
dictator he abolished the
califit and this this caused a global
outcry among the the Muslims of the
world because they were they they loved
their Khalif and whatever I don't know
um so in
India uh a number of prominent Muslim uh
politicians Etc they started they
launched the move mement called the
kilat movement which was to restore
which was a movement to restore the C
calipat and the objective was to unify
the Muslims of India they knew that
sitting in India and turkey is so far
away constan Noble is so far away we
can't really have a say in what happens
but let's launch a movement to bring
awareness among Indian Muslims and to
unify Indian Muslims in a common
cause um and there were a number of
Muslim politicians involved in this so
Mr Gandhi Mr mandas Gandhi he said wow
what a wonderful thing let us also
participate in this
matter
um so Mr Gandhi um said that we support
the the the congress party supports the
the khilafat movement okay and Mr Gandhi
was a very prominent politician by the
time and so he brought the kilat
movement into the mainstream
consciousness of India until that time
it was just a Fring
kind of movement some politicians were
pushing for it and their their great
objective was to unify the Indian
Muslims through this movement but nobody
knew about those politicians I forget
the name names of the politicians many
of them eventually became a big deal
because of Mr Gandhi's
support this was a fringe movement
nobody in India knew or cared about this
and it had no impact it had no relevance
in India what happens in Constantinople
has no relevance in India especially in
the 1920
days and it had nothing to do with the
Indian Freedom struggle at all it had
nothing to do with the British
occupation of India and the
British oppression and destruction of
India's economy and all that nothing it
had nothing to do with us but Mr Gandhi
in his wisdom said that we need to
support this movement so he brought this
obscure Fringe movement into the
mainstream and it told everybody all
Indians who supported him that we must
support the Kila movement so everybody
started supporting
it and it made those obscure politicians
who started the movement in India it
made them into very into a very big deal
eventually they became the leaders of
the partition movement of India many of
them okay they would have been they
would have remained in obscurity had Mr
Gandhi not elevated them out of
nothingness into the national mainstream
and most Indians who were supporting
this movement they had no idea what this
movement was kilat K kilat sounds like
Kila which means against right so most
Indians thought that it's a movement to
oppose the British it is in Kila of the
British so let's let's support this
movement most Indians had no idea they
had no idea this was a movement to to
support an Islamic caliphate they had no
idea it was a movement in support of
sharia law and so on so forth okay they
had no idea about this so Mr Gandhi just
LED everybody along it it and it
essentially
was the the
germination of the movement for India's
partition the kilat movement became the
partition movement the the idea of
partition may have started in the 19th
century in the minds of one or two
people and they wrote about this and so
on but such a movement never became
mainstream until Mr Gandhi brought it
into the mainstream so this movement was
not necessary at all Mr Gandhi support
his support for this movement was I just
don't understand the logic why was it
needed to do this
it was not necessary it did not unite
Indians those who supported Mr Gandhi
supported the movement it was not a
movement that United Indians but it
brought the
anti-nationals in into prominence it
gave them tremendous political
Capital it brought them into the
national mainstream Consciousness and it
gave them the political Capital to start
the partition movement and that's what
eventually led to the partition
of
India yeah and I have this this talk on
YouTube on another Channel called the
Turkish origins of India's partition
maybe I should revisit that and do that
again for this
channel yeah anyhow a good question
shra spandan mukarji says why are
Indians portrayed as impoverished in
series depicting ramayan and Mahabharat
wasn't India the richest country country
back
then you see the problem is that these
people who who direct these these
series and all that these people have no
idea of the true history of India I
remember when I when I had seen many
many many years ago the original romance
series it showed Indians in poverty in
that also there was no poverty in India
back then I don't know how many
thousands of years ago India was
especially during the Raman era a more
agrarian more uh pastoral kind of
society it wasn't the the uh during the
Raman ramayan era India was not the
urbanized society that it was during the
snu sarasti era or the Mahabharat but
India was there was no poverty in India
whatsoever before the tury and and
Christian occupations of India so these
individ ual who direct these series they
have no idea of India's true history and
they think that India has always been
like this and that's why people are
depicted in poty in in these TV series
ramay and maharat it's it's it's sad to
see that it's so annoying uh to see how
history is distorted maybe they're
they're well-meaning people or whatever
but yeah there are lots of distortions
of history and of the original stories
in series TV serials about Mahabharat
and ramayan and because of this people
who watch who learn about the mahabad
and rayan from these series they they
absorb these these these these fake
stories and they believe that someone
like kov for example was Superior to
Arjun and he was uh he was discriminated
against because of his
cast and aavia was also discriminated
against because of his cast and so on
all these stupid nonsensical
uh delusions enter people's minds
because of the way these these TV
serials are crafted it's
terrible mudra makana says I saw your
video on delusions that India has and I
wanted to ask a follow-up question where
do you think India really stands with
respect to superpowers like the Us and
other countries like China Russia Etc I
see that India is certainly on the right
path of success and becoming a great
country at least that's a general
sentiment but in reality where does
India really stand and when and how do
you think India will reach the top of
the level of top Nations like the US
India is
currently look I look at the world from
a very realistic hard power perspective
to hell with soft power and all this
nonsense what matters is hard power hard
power is economic might plus military
military might and some other factors
that are all material factors okay so
from that perspective India is the
fourth most powerful nation in the world
number one in the world you have the US
the most powerful Nation superp power
number two is Russia which is about half
as strong as the US so if if the US has
a hard power score of let's say 100 then
Russia has a score of 50 number three is
China and China is about 20 on the hard
power scale roughly almost a third of
Russia and India is about five on the
hard power score about a
fourth roughly a fourth of China a third
or fourth maybe six or something on the
hard power scale India and then you have
France which is about five slightly be
below
India so that's where India stands
India's power is about one3 of China
about um
oneth of Russia and about 120th that of
the US that's where we stand stand in
the world's pecking order number four
but nowhere close to the top three
that's where we stand with respect to
genuine big Powers okay uh that that's
simply the way it is and if people get
upset to hear that well the facts don't
care about anyone's feelings now uh is
India on the path to success yes and
no there are there are good things
happening in India no question about it
India's economy has done tremendously
well the past 10 years we have almost
doubled our GDP in the past 10 years a
lot of infrastructure has been created
in the last 10 years lot of
infrastructure highways Railways
airports what not has been built in the
past last 10 years tremendous progress
um extreme poverty is almost at
negligible levels now in India nobody
starves to death anymore okay uh so much
has improved in India Indians today
genuinely Aspire for for so much more
and lots of Indians believe we are
almost close to being a superpower so
that's how much India has changed in the
past 10 20 whatever years so a lot is
going in the right direction India's
economic growth India is the only major
economy that has zero chance of res
which will keep on growing so that's
again great for India our military
strength is good what is also great is
that we are an independent space Power
we don't need to depend on anybody for
satellite launches or anything that's
great for India that's a great asset to
have and what really ensures our our
sovereignty is the nuclear deterrent
that we have and the means to deliver
those nuclear uh Warheads all of that is
great so we are definitely on the right
track in all these things no question
about it but we have significant
problems the education system is a
disaster and because of the education
system how poor it is Indians live in a
delusional World Indians don't know how
to think they are afraid to ask
questions they don't even know what
questions to ask of themselves of others
or anything they don't know how to think
critically they it's very easy to fool
Indians through through propaganda and
media narratives um and so on so many
problems with the education system that
needs to be fixed that's number one
number two India's biggest problem is
corruption what you going to do about
that is anything being done about that
unfortunately
no third the political system is
completely unsuitable for a nation like
India the Westminster democracy that we
have the the parliamentary system a much
better system of democracy would have
been the presidential system for India
in which things get done much faster and
the gigantically bloated inefficient
bureaucracy is a huge drag on India and
like I said corruption is the worst
thing that India is suffering from and
nobody even dares to speak about it the
whole nation allegedly runs on
corruption and then we have issues like
100 million illegal immigrants at least
in India Bangladesh is ringas and
cookies and what not so many issues so
all these issues will ensure that India
never becomes a great power we'll keep
on going in the right direction but
we'll never become genuinely great we'll
never fulfill our true potential so
these things need to be addressed we
have the potential to be the greatest
nation in the world the most powerful
nation in the world but right now we are
not visha Guru we are vishak
Ki and we are not superpower we are
number four
barely and nowhere close to even China
forget about Russia or the US these are
hard
facts we have all the potential but we
need drastic reforms significant
surgery who will dare to do it which
leader will have the coones to do it is
the question uh apologies for that
Spanish
word geopolitical du says Viv ramaswami
is no longer in Doge but he is
contesting the Ohio governor election
what's he trying to
achieve VI ramaswami has seen quite a
decline in his political fortunes he was
at one time in contention against
President Trump for the Republican
nomination for president
of course he stood down after he made a
significant impact and became very much
front and center in the National
Consciousness in the US so it made him a
very big deal in the US um then he was
hoping for a significant cabinet cabinet
position under Trump's presidency did
not happen he was made number two IND
Doge under Elon Musk and then it looks
like he was sh shunted out of Doge
itself the department of government
efficiency and right now the public
perception of him his public perception
isn't great because of a tweet he put
out in which he criticized the the
American population for not having high
enough standards imagine a brown man
criticizing white people for not having
high enough standard so it doesn't work
like that in the US so yeah that's gone
against
him
um so um yeah right now the the opinion
the public opinion of him isn't great so
he's no longer anywhere at the the top
level uh and he's not not even in Doge
now youon musk probably had him shunted
out in when the opportunity presented
itself and now he is uh running for the
governorship of Ohio so look VI has made
his money he's a billionaire whichever
way he made it whatever doesn't matter
he's a billionaire he has no worries
about money or anything career he wants
to be AIG deal worldwide he wants to
have a political career
he hopes to be the president of the US
one day yeah
so because so to do that to become the
president you to prove yourself
politically you know either prove
yourself in the Trump Administration
maybe as as one of the one of the
cabinet one of the members of the
cabinet like the uh Secretary of State
which is the foreign minister or
something similar or you have to have
political experience as the governor of
a
state so if you are the governor of a
big state like Ohio significantly large
State and if you do it well for number
of years then yeah it gives you the it
tells the people that yeah this guy can
govern and he is capable so yeah he did
not get anything significant in the
Trump cabinet anything significant at
all so now it makes sense for him to run
for the governorship of Ohio Ohio his
first job is to win the governorship
which itself is difficult and if if he's
able to win then he has to govern well
and and and do a great job as Governor
so it's a long road ahead of him lots of
obstacles it's not going to be easy but
what he's trying to achieve is to
demonstrate to the nation that he is
serious and that he is capable and that
and what he's eventually trying to
achieve is to someday become the
president of the US that is uh that's
his agenda that's the ambition that he
has but he has to be careful and
he's a very smart guy VI rahas Swami
super smart guy but he needs to be
careful he's not he doesn't become super
annoying see there are different kind
various kinds of smart people there are
some of in a classroom there are some
kids who are the teachers pet they'll
sit in the front bench they'll raise
their hand for every question and
they'll have the right answer every time
super smart always the right answer very
obedient the teachers love them and then
are the smart kids who sit in the back
benches who don't care about answering
questions but they end up being the
Millionaires and billionaires so viic is
one of those who was in the front
benches apparently it looks like and he
also become a billionaire but such kids
can be very annoying the kid who knows
everything the kid who has something to
teach everybody else all the time you
got to be careful about that VI is in
danger of being that annoying kid right
now so he needs to be careful let's see
how it goes for him
okay we are reaching the end of today's
session still some time to go let's take
some more questions himansu says I've
observed that within the within Canada
immigrants from India tend to socialize
primarily within their own Regional
groups for example Gujarati individuals
often associate with other gujaratis
while those from Kerala will form their
own circles as a result there seems to
be a lack of overall Unity how can we
Foster a more inclusive and cohesive
Indian Community where people from
diverse backgrounds interact and connect
with each other a good question that's
true Indians wherever we go wherever we
are outside India we will have these
small Circles of people who speak the
same
language gujaratis will be only with
gujaratis punjabis all punjabis together
tamils all Tamil together telugus all
telugus together malis are all malis
together all
separate right
that's that's very common among Indians
forget about that
okay if you have lived in a hostel as a
student then you will see that even in
hostels there are these small Circles of
of of kids who speak the same language
and they'll all be friends together
that's just a thing you see among
Indians Indians seem to prioritize their
subnational identities more than their
national
identity it's always about language
sometimes it's about uh relig religion
sometimes apparently sometimes it's
about region and and so on and that's
just an Indian characteristic we are
such a diverse
nation that this is how it is and the
only thing that can the only thing that
can bring Indians together is if there's
an existential threat from
somewhere so I don't know it would be
nice to see Indians all merge together
and and be and you know behave as one
common group instead of always having
the
subdivisions um another thing you see
among Indians outside of India
especially in North America is they like
you said they have their own circles and
they tend to not mingle too much with
the
locals so you can spend a whole
week in even if you're a professional in
in in the US let's say you can spend
most of your time speaking an Indian
language because you have so many
Indians around you and you'll hardly
interact with with the with the locals
the
Americans you see that all the time in
the US so that's this this insulation
kind of approach that Indians have they
need to break out of it mingle with
everybody mingle with other Indians who
speak other languages than yours why do
you need to be so insular like that so
I'm not sure how to change this mindset
the only thing that can change the
mindset if if there's an exist
existential threat to India that's the
only thing that can probably bring all
Indians together but we don't want that
of course don't
we
okay abinav deep says in this modern
world marriage is becoming a joke some
women openly say just attached to
marriage for two three years and they
then take alimony and enjoy yourself
some suicide cases of men are frequently
appearing in the media nowaday Family
Values are Vanishing is it all is this
all because women have more
constitutional rights
between men and women women modern women
do not care about family values what's
the
deal uh there are lots of
issues first of all yeah Constitution
and law right our constitution the
Indian constitution and Indian laws are
not rooted in India's cultural and
civilizational
values absolutely not at all our
Constitution and our laws are Western in
nature absolutely nothing to do with
Indian culture so the have Western
values and
morality and then you have the the case
of the Indian education system which is
a colonial system you may realize it or
not it's a colonial system it doesn't
teach India is the only nation in the
world where the education system doesn't
teach you your culture and your values
it deines you it appro you and distances
you from your
culture so is it people's fault that
they don't care about family values
cultural tradition or any of that it's
not their fault the education system
does that to you the media does it to
you the entertainment industry does it
to you the laws do it to
you everything so yeah there people are
hardly attached to the culture
anymore people don't even know what
their culture is and then you have uh
the law the Indian law the Constitution
that is just like the Western laws so
there have been so many cases like this
I mean there was this cricketer recently
who married this woman for a year or two
I don't know how long and apparently I
hear that he has to pay her like 50
crores of Al money why why what has he
deserved done to deserve this if someone
marries you for two years and then she
divorces you does it mean she gets to
have 50 crores what the hell and
apparently I hear that the law always
favors the women or men and so on it's
it's a mess it's an absolute mess there
are so many issues to unpack in this the
the the Constitution and laws are
completely alien to Indian culture and
civilizational values completely
completely completely foreign in nature
it's like we are still under foreign
occupation and foreign laws apply to us
and also we are still under foreign
occupation and a foreign education
system is thrust upon us that derates us
and the this the end result is all
this the end result is all this so we're
going to
see you know over time higher rates of
divorce and
all that and the system victimizes men
always so if there's a divorce the the
look I have nothing against against any
gender I don't care everybody should be
treated treated equally the system
cannot be loaded against one gender
which is men today so you know people
accuse the whole system is is rigged
against men Essen it looks like so if
there's a divorce the the men the man
will have to pay I don't know what
uh huge alimony and uh maintenance and
child rights also are are an issue you
know um who gets to who gets custody of
the child that's also an issue and so on
lots of issues the whole system is an
absolute mess there's so much potential
in India but the whole system is
destroying it so sad to see
this okay the question is please take up
this question I've been asking for a
long time the question is given the
Paramount knowledge you have of various
Fields why didn't you become an i IAS or
ifs officer you could have easily scored
air all India rank
one um I was told that as a kid that why
don't you I mean as a student when I was
a student uh in in College University uh
people used to tell me why don't you go
and apply for the I you know um um
whatever that exam is and you'll do
really
well so I never bothered to take do that
exam and try to become an I if IPS
whatever officer it never appealed to
me um look if you clear the exam you're
going to become either an IAS or IPS or
ifs officer you're going to be a
government servant ifs is is a very rare
case at that time as a kid as a student
I didn't even know much about the Indian
Foreign Service it was mainly the IAS
that on people spoke about so what
happens you become a bureaucrat if you
do well you going to become a collector
or a district magistrate or some
powerful position in which case you
going to have a whole District under you
and everybody is going to come to you
and S do sir s s s sir to you but the
truth is that you're going to report to
a politician that politician may be 10
fail possibly and you're going to have
to do yes or yeser to him that
politician and you you just a public
servant and the whole system allegedly
to a very large extent one years
allegedly that it is allegedly very
allegedly corrupt so you're going to
have to be part of that and that never
appeal to me taking orders
from
people who you should never have to take
orders from and participating in in
corrupt allegedly in corruption aiding
and abetting alleged corruption all
that just taking orders you don't really
have any power of your own yeah you can
feel all powerful when people come to a
supplicants to to have you solve the
problems it feel you may feel like
you're powerful but you are just taking
orders you just just a machine in a
bigger machine this has never appealed
to me you lo you lose all your autonomy
you're
always at someone's
service you lose all autonomy you lose
your Independence your freedom this has
never appealed to me that's why I never
did that so that's the answer to your
[Laughter]
question okay um God's servant says I'm
a former powerlifter and a fitness freak
I follow my sonan Dharma I grew up
eating meat and fish and also worshiped
the Great goddess now I'm practicing um
plant-based diet which has been 1.5
years now and I'm back to powerlifting
is my entrance is complete good within
this 1.5 years I can see my health
deteriorates my question is is it
allowed in sanatan D to eat fish and
meats is food a question of morality I
also know that supporting poultry and
eating meat greatly hampers the planet I
don't know what to do what should I do
this is a very controversial question
and a lot of people will hate me for
what I what I'll
say look in sanatan Dharma in all
dharmic religions in in the dharmic
world whether it's j Dharma bodha Dharma
Hindu Dharma or or whatever else you may
have or may not
have in
Dharma it is always
preferable to live a life of
nonviolence that doesn't cause cruelty
to any living beings as far as possible
that is preferable Allah life of ainsa
is preferable so what it means is that
being a vegetarian is preferable and it
is seen as Superior to being a
non-vegetarian okay that is
unambiguously clear in Dharma in in San
Dharma but this comes with caveats let's
say your Dharma or your karma is that of
a
warrior okay let's say you are a
chhatria let's say you're a king you're
Raj whatever and 500 years ago and your
job is to defend civilization from the
The
Barbarians now if you are eating a
nonviolent plant-based diet do you think
you'll be able to do your your your duty
properly no that's why it is acceptable
in s Dharma for people in certain
occupations that need more energy and
protein and all that to eat meat it is
acceptable absolutely acceptable some
people may not like what I say well I
can't please everybody sorry I'm just
going to say what I know is right so it
is preferable in sanatan Dharma to not
eat meat to be vegetarian but it is
acceptable to eat meat if you want to
live a certain kind of Lifestyle as long
as you don't cause don't cause any
unnecessary
cruelty so there are ways of acquiring
meat that are less cruel than other ways
you know what I mean I think we all know
what it means so do it the right way I
think it is okay as a dharmic person to
eat meat if you want to live a certain
lifestyle and serve society and do good
in the world and maybe it makes you
happier so you can do it but always
remember Don't Be Cruel cause as little
cruelty in the world as
possible so yeah it is morally Superior
to be non-vegetarian it is to be
vegetarian it is morally Superior to be
completely nonviolent but in the real
world
you know things don't always work that
way so I would say that you know it's
okay to eat meat that's what I would say
if you find that being vegetarian makes
you weaker and your health is
deteriorating go for it you know I'm
sure even various uh religious uh Saints
I don't know which one it was okay I'll
not take names because I don't remember
but you know many gurus have also said
that it's okay to eat meat if you need
to
um yeah there you have
it
um life is Meaningful says what do you
think about religion's impact on science
and technology in India are you an
atheist and are atheists generally
smarter see when we talk about religion
the term religion it doesn't really
apply to to
civilizational things like San Dharma
the the dharmic system is not a
religious system religious is a foreign
term to
India um there have been if you if you
go back in Indian history and look at
all the great scientists and Scholars of
India whether it is brahmagupta whether
it is Arya bhat whether it is whoever
they all been deeply deeply
religious but also been the greatest of
of astronomers and mathematicians and
whatnot look at
ramanujan rahmanan was an incredibly
intense devotee of goddess namagiri he
said that she used to come to him in in
his dreams and give him the equations
that he would have to wake up and
quickly note
down not a single one of his equations
has been proven to be wrong those
equations are shocking when you look at
them so look when it comes to Hindu
Dharma when it comes to the dharmic
umbrella dharmic system it is it has it
has never been anti science it's always
been a system of inquiry of skepticism
of learning something new don't ever be
dogmatic that's always been the system
so in India it's always been it's always
been an enabler of Science and
Technology okay um am I an atheist I'm
not an atheist absolutely not are
atheists generally
smarter let me just say it as it is I
think atheists are generally not always
but generally
Dumber okay uh question from Twitter
from X Cricket question by Robbie plant
one of my favorite singers
uh is legs spin a dying art today and
which is the most difficult ball
variation to bowl in cricket good
question let me do I have ball yeah have
a ball
here that's a tennis ball Cricket
question well is leg spin a dying art
today leg spin has never been a dying
art but it's a rare art among all the
different kinds of uh bowling variations
off spin leg spin medium pace left arm P
fast bowling whatever among all of these
different kinds of bowling leg speed is
the hardest to master and it's also the
hardest to play if you're a
batsman it's the hardest thing to master
because it's unnatural the movement is
unnatural you to spin the ball with your
wrist not with your fingers this is off
spin that's leg Spin and you have so few
leg Spinners typically at any period in
time in history there was a rarity of a
time when you had three leg Spinners
mushak Ahmed sh Anil Kum they were all
different from each other so leg spin is
extremely difficult to master or to even
bow reasonably well today who are the
leg Spinners that we have uh today you
have Kip yav a lefty leg spinner you
have tabz shami also a lefty leg spinner
chinan bowler you
have what's the Australian
guy um what's his name zampa Adam zai I
think it's Adam zampa and who else do
you have today I don't I can't think of
anybody else today so we don't have too
many leg Spinners today um it's because
it's so hard leg spin is so hard it's so
hard to control and land the ball with
the right amount of revolutions and land
the ball in the right place and so on
it's so hard you would see leg spers bow
way too many full tosses generally it's
because it's so hard to to control it's
because of the biomechanics of the
action and the physics of the action but
if you get it right it's incredibly
difficult to play as a batsman so it's
not a dying art it's it's it's a rare
art it's it's the Dark Art of cricket
leg spin
is um which is the most difficult ball
to bowl in
cricket also it's a flipper it's a it's
a leg spin variation in in leg spin you
have different deliveries you go the
standard leg spinner which is this way
then you have the top spinner which you
bowl like that okay and then you have
the googly which you bowl like that with
your back of the hand facing the bowler
back man your your front arm also drops
a little when you bowl a googly so but
the flipper is ball that's almost
impossible to pick and extremely
difficult to bowl because a flipper you
you load up like like a top spinner but
you you flip it out from the back of
your hand so you you do it like that
like that you know you do almost like
click your fingers that way it's
incredibly hard to master and incredibly
hard to play I mean you can't even
usually see it coming so today do you
see anybody bowling a flipper in in
cricket any leg spinner Kip yadav tabes
shami uh Adam zampa who was it South
African Pakistani guy recently Imran
Tahir was it he didn't Bowl The Flipper
nobody bowls The Flipper today did Kum
Bowl The Flipper he did not did mushak
Ahmed Bowl The Flipper he did not Abdul
khad bowled it Shane ju was the best
bowler of flippers ever but the flipper
is really hard to bowl I think it's the
hardest Bowl in cricket and it puts a
tremendous amount of strain on this
muscle the muscle of your middle finger
because generally these two fingers the
middle finger and the thumb that that's
involved so yeah it's the I think the
flipper is the hardest ball to ball and
that's why nobody balls it and how do I
know all this because I used to be exp
SP as a kid uh I was LE until I was like
12 13 then I grew taller so I switched
to bowling fast and I I played a bit of
cricket uh in school and a bit in
college as well a little bit so yeah I I
used to B beenin and it's it's it's an
incredibly U it's a dark Ard if you can
bow well my God nobody can play you it
so yeah I used to bow that why did I
switch to fast bowling because I grew
taller and bigger and stronger and I
found that in India apart from legs spin
the one thing that frightens batsman
even more is fast bowling so if you have
the ability to do that do
that so there you have
it uh do we have any questions I think
we have one or two more questions or
should I just take questions from the
live chat now maybe I'll just do that
all right Peoples Peoples
uh AK Prem says kib bows the The Flipper
really I've never seen K bow The Flipper
do you even know what the flipper is
it's not the top spinner it is a
delivery that goes straight but the
flipper is flicked down like this with
the top spinner kind of action but it's
flicked flick down like this it is a
ball so I'll tell you what a flipper is
like it's a ball that will float further
towards the batsman because of the
Magnus effect because you you have put
this back spin on the ball so the ball
will float further towards the batsman
and after pitching it it stays low it's
kids on and you generally Bowl The
Flipper faster and you make it look like
a shorter ball like like a ball that's
too short and the batsman tries to cut
or pull but then it comes kids onto the
batsman at like super speed
and yeah Kip does not ball The Flipper I
assure you he balls a top spinner I'm
sure he bows a top spinner which is a
different delivery which is a ball that
loops and dips and then bounces more The
Flipper is the exact opposite of a top
spinner it doesn't Loop it doesn't dip
it floats further towards the batsman it
comes it it pitches further uh further
towards the batsman than the bats
expects and it stays low it skids so
it's a very different kind of ball
Kar says my passion for Pure math is
waning I find it too abstract and filled
with theorems and proofs I once aspired
to be a
mathematician but now I feel uncertain
should I pursue a Masters or not look if
you have lost your passion The Thrill Is
Gone Like BB King would say then don't
do it don't force yourself to do
that pure math is not for everybody you
need to be slightly insane to be someone
who goes into pure math because there's
no real career out outside of a
university in pure math as an app
mathematician there's CER everywhere you
can go into the stock market you can go
into anything there's a huge demand for
Applied mathematicians pure math it's
not for
everybody so if your passion for Pure
math is winning then don't pursue a
master's degree in pure math go into
applied math or go into some an Allied
field like physics or or or or or or
engineering or whatever you obviously if
you have mathematical skills then you
can use them elsewhere so I would say
Don't force yourself to to to follow a
passion that is no longer there be
practical and use the skills that you've
acquired uh in a in a in a practical
way
okay
um okay let's see what else do we have
um 2 35 but I answered him
so uh Amisha says why are Indian
politicians obsessed with orze every now
and then and now he's being discussed
left always Praises him and the right
side doesn't like him what's why is this
happening I think the media creates a
lot of these
controversies okay and certain
politicians of certain inclinations have
this Affinity towards or Z which is
unfortunate but it is what it
is so or Zeb was one of the CR cruelest
and bloodthirstiest Kings who ruled
India Foreigner despite being born in
India doesn't make him an Indian he
tried his best to destroy India's
culture civilization all that he if you
look at the New York Times New York
Times statistics by a left
organization he is one of the he killed
at least 10 million Indians according to
New York Times statistics and so on
whatever the numbers are
he was definitely a genocide a
perpetrator of genocide so obviously
he's going to evoke strong feelings
among among Indians and most Indians
obviously will despise him for for the
horrific acts that he did um so yeah but
the
left in India the left is anti-national
mostly most of them not all I'm sure
some of them may be genuinely leftists
from a sense of believing that it's
right but I would say many leftists are
international not all I'm sure some of
them are nice so the left is
anti-national most of it so they will
praise Him obviously and so on so in
India the news cycle is full of shouting
and outrage and and people yelling at
each other so it's it's it's tailor made
for the new cycle and then politicians
get involved because politicians also
want to be part of the the shoutings so
that you know they can uh further their
whatever agenda is currently there today
so that's how it
goes um
okay what else do we have uh I've
already spoken about rir so I'll not go
into the matter again
um okay let me see see this is why I
don't take generally a whole session
only from the live chat because I to
look at all the questions and uh try and
find a good
question
um okay Sergeant Skyland says will there
be a new Nation called
balistan we'll see we we know right
viewers of the ask abijit show know very
well that Pakistan is a artificial
temporary Nation a temporary artificial
nation and sooner or later it will uh it
will it will take a different shape and
form
so so Nations like baluchistan
eventually May emerge out of Pakistan it
probably is a matter of time p and kber
pakun kber pakun goes back to
Afghanistan it will be nice to see that
yes our Pon friends can have the
territories back and G baltistan po
comes back to India punjabian can remain
independent on its own and uh cind synu
Desh becomes independent again and
hopefully baluchistan too it will happen
sooner or later how sooner or how later
depends on a variety of factors but it's
look artificial temporary Nations don't
last forever so yeah
T just says I am doing well I'm glad to
hear that sir I I know that you had some
health issues please take care of your
health and I'm happy to know that you're
doing well um you want to hear my views
about Trump's latest tweet about
sanctioning Russia well I'm not aware of
it let me see let's go
to Trump
Twitter uh let's put that on the screen
and let's let's try and take a look at
this
together Trump's latest tweet about
sectioning Russia so let's see tweets by
real Donald Trump what's he have to
say DJ Trump um what do we have what do
we have thank you for
joining zilinski this is from March 1
this is for February 20 this is old so
let me see the pus
account let's see the pus account which
uh what does he have to say
here J 23 hours
okay let's see this based on the fact
that Russia is absolutely pounding
Ukraine on the battlefield right now I'm
strongly considering large scale banking
sanctions sanctions and tariffs on
Russia until the ceasefire and final
settlement of Peace on peace is reached
to Russia and Ukraine get to the table
right now before it's too late thank you
okay so this is standard negotiating
tactic I'm I'm glad you spoke about this
I was not aware of this this uh is from
March 7th it's from today 8:00 p.m. okay
just an hour before I started this live
stream so I wasn't aware of this latest
tweet
so what Trump is saying is that uh so
look what happens
now Putin and Trump have spoken on the
telephone right and they both agreed
that we need to come to the negotiating
table table and finalize this the the
ceasefire
agreement that has already been
discussed a few days ago then zalinsky
comes to the US to finalize the the the
minerals deal but he completely upends
the thing and goes uh and and insults
his hosts and doesn't sign the deal and
then he goes to Europe and then the
European nations say that we will keep
the war going keep it going
on you cannot have a ceas fire without
involving the European nations who the
hell are they to say that to the two big
Powers right so when this sort of
situation happens Putin will say okay
let me start a new military offensive
just to remind everybody that I am in a
position if I want to completely take
the UK whole of Ukraine without a Seas
fire so then Trump says okay this cannot
happen so Trump is just putting a word
of caution over there so he's saying to
Russia and Ukraine get to the table
right now which means Russia essentially
and in Ukraine means zinski needs to
just sign on the doted line otherwise
you know he's in trouble so yeah Trump
uh is also there so so that's that
that's why Trump has put out this tweet
so probably Russia is now uh reminding
the world that you know what if you guys
don't want a ceasefire I'm perfectly
okay with that I can take Ukraine just
without a ceasefire so Trump is just
putting a word of ction on there okay
okay okay let's not go get too head of
ourselves let's finalize the deal so
that's the deal very good to know that
you very good that you pointed this out
and we could discuss
this and I think with that we're going
to end today's
session all right thank you so much for
for all the questions it was a great
session uh really enjoyed the the last
little segment in which we took
questions from the live chat and I will
see you next week all right in the next
live stream so thank you so much
everybody take care keep asking
questions keep raising your standards
and I will see you in next week's live
stream until then take care thank you so
much bye